翻译：@隐秀_（seriouszyx）
So SLLists, they have some great advantages over IntLists.
与 IntList 相比，SLList 有很大的优势
We can cache data inside of them,
我们可以在其中缓存数据
and they're generally easier to use.
而且它们通常更容易使用
We'll see now that there's another cool advantage we can confer to them,
来看看另一个能赋予它的很酷的优势
which is to allow ourselves to represent the empty list.
允许表示空链表
That is, sometimes, when you make lists,
有时你创建 List
you don't have anything you want to put in it yet,
还没什么要放进去的东西
so it's natural to be able to instantiate an empty list.
因此自然应该能够实例化空链表
So let's modify our code.
修改一下代码
And we'll start with a constructor
从构造函数开始
to get a sense of what that really means.
了解那意味着什么
So this constructor, the goal is--
这个构造器的目标是...
creates an empty SLList.
创建空的 SLList
So that means I need to set my instance variables here to represent an empty list.
我们需要在这里设置实例变量来表示空链表
It seems natural to say the size is 0.
当然了 size 是0
But what about first?
first 呢？
What should first be?
first 应该是什么？
Well, rather than making a new int node,
与其创建一个 IntNode
one possibility is to simply say that first is null, right?
将 first 设为 null 更简单对吗？
There's nothing there.
那里什么都没有
And in that way, when we create a new SLList--
这样，当我们创建一个新的 SLList 时
OK, well, new SLList.
new SLList()
Don't put anything in there at all.
别往里面放任何东西
This should be an empty SLList.
这是空的 SLList
We put 10 at the front, 5 at the front, and 20 at the back.
我们把10放在前面，5放在前面，20放在后面
We tried running this, and it prints out l.size,
我们试过了，打印 L.size()
and we get 3, which seems good.
得到 3，看起来不错
But who knows. Maybe there's some issue here lurking.
但谁知道呢，也许里面藏着一些问题
So let's use the visualizer to make sure everything works.
所以使用可视化工具来确保一切正常工作
OK. So we run this code.
运行这段代码
We step through a bit.
少走几步
And we see that after we've created--
我们看到...
after we've finished this line of code,
在我们完成这行代码之后
we end up with an empty list.
最终会得到一个空链表
L points at this middleman data structure where the size is 0
L 指向中间人，size 是0
and there's no actual list.
现在没有真正的 List
And notice it doesn't point to anything.
注意它没有指向任何东西
And by the time it is done, we end up with a data structure that looks nice.
所有执行后，我们最终得到了一个看起来不错的数据结构
Now, first points at a naked recursive list.
first 指向一个裸递归 List
The size is 3.
size 是3
All seems well.
似乎一切正常
Now, it turns out there's actually a very subtle bug,
但事实证明这是一个非常微妙的错误
which you're welcome to think about and ponder,
欢迎你仔细思考
but I'm just going to spoil,
但我马上揭晓
which is that if we try to add to the end of an empty list, we'll run into trouble.
如果我们试图在空链表末尾添加，就会遇到麻烦
So let me give you an example.
举个例子
We create an empty list,
我们创建一个空链表
and then we try and add to the end of it, it crashes.
然后我们试着把它加到末尾，就崩溃了
We get an exception.
得到异常
And this is something that is not obvious
这件事情不明显
looking at the structure of addLast code
看看 addLast 的代码
until you think about the following.
直到你想到以下几点
Suppose we have an empty list.
假设我们有一个空链表
If first is null, well then p gets set equal to null.
如果 first 为 null，那么 p 被设置为 null
And then we say, while p.next is not equal to null.
而 p.next != null
Well, p is null.
p 是 null
So you try to go to the nullth position,
尝试访问 null 的位置
go to the next variable of null, and that causes a null pointer exception.
访问 null 的 next 变量，这会导致 null 指针异常
You can't ask-- you can't go to a memory location null and try and get next.
你不能访问 null 的内存位置并且得到 next
It doesn't make sense.
这没有意义
So this bug is not obvious.
所以这个错误并不明显
It's totally easy.
这非常简单
Like, the only reason I know this bug exists is because I taught this lecture before,
我知道这个 bug 的原因是我之前教过这门课
and I've thought about this a lot,
我想了很久
and it's not anything that would be at all obvious to you.
对你来说，这并不是什么显而易见的事情
And in a later lecture, again, we'll talk about how to test your code in a more robust way.
在后面的课程中，我们将再次讨论如何更健壮地测试你的代码
But here, I'm just giving away that this bug exists.
但在这里，我只是透露这个 bug 的存在
So your goal now--
所以你现在的目标是...
to make a long story short--
长话短说
is to fix this bug.
修复这个 bug
Make it so that this code right here works.
这样才能让这里的代码正常工作
So I'll give you a chance to ponder this to think about how you can change addLast,
给你们一个机会来思考如何改变 addLast
and I'll spoil it in a moment.
一会揭晓
One possible solution-- but not the only one--
一个可能的解决方案，但不是唯一的
is to say, OK, well, the problem occurs if the first is equal to null.
就是说，如果 first 是 null，问题就发生了
So I'll just say, if first is equal to null,
所以如果 first == null
do something special.
做点特别的事
What should I do?
怎么做？
Well, in that case, rather than changing the existing list,
在这种情况下，与其改变现有的 List
I have to actually create a new one because there's nothing there.
最好创建一个新的，因为那里什么都没有
I'll have x null.
参数是 x 和 null
And then I don't want to do the rest, so I'll return.
其他的不执行了，直接返回
So this code here, if I run it, it works fine, right?
运行这些代码，工作得很好
And I add to the end of list, it is no longer crashing.
在 List 末尾添加，它就不再崩溃了
And this fix-- not that I've proven it to you,
这个解决方法...我没证明过
but it does work perfectly well.
但它确实工作得很好
So that's one way to approach this problem.
所以这是解决这个问题的一种方式
But it's a little ugly.
但是有点难看
Look at our addLast method.
看看我们的 addLast 方法
I mean, it's just getting a little bloated.
它变得有点臃肿了
So what I'm going to do next it just is going to describe an alternate strategy that I think is better.
所以下一步要做的就是描述一种我认为更好的替代策略
翻译：@隐秀_（seriouszyx）